<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<sect1 id="release-6-8-2">
  <title>Release notes for version 6.8.2</title>

  <para>
    6.8.2 is a bugfix release over 6.8.1. Many bugs in the compiler,
    libraries and build system have been fixed. However, most library
    APIs have not changed, so code that worked with 6.8.1 should
    continue to work with 6.8.2. The notable exceptions, as well as the
    user interface changes, are listed below.
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The <option>--print-docdir</option> for GHC has been removed,
        as there were some problems with the implementation. We'll
        revisit this area in a future release.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Standalone deriving declarations now respect scope: You can't
        derive a <literal>Show</literal> instance, for example, unless
        all the constructors are in scope.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        GHCi now treats all input as unicode, except for the Windows
        console where we do the correct conversion from the current
        code page.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In GHCi, ":" now repeats the last command.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In GHCi, <literal>:{ ..lines.. :}</literal> can be used to
        give multi-line commands. This is mainly useful in
        <filename>.ghci</filename> files.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In GHCi, <literal>:show languages</literal> shows the
        active language extensions and <literal>:show packages</literal>
        shows the loaded packages.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        In GHCi, <literal>:def!</literal> now overwrites a previous
        command with the same name, <literal>:def</literal> on its own
        lists the defined macros, and <literal>:undef f g</literal>
        undefines both <literal>f</literal> and <literal>g</literal>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        There is now a variant, <literal>:browse!</literal>,
        of <literal>:browse</literal>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Various changes have been made to GHC's internals, so there are
        some differences in the API exposed by the ghc package. Most
        notably, <literal>checkAndLoadModule</literal> has now been
        implemented.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The version of base has been increased from 3.0.0.0 to 3.0.1.0.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The version of Cabal has been increased from 1.2.2.0 to 1.2.3.0.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The version of containers has been increased from 0.1.0.0 to 0.1.0.1.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The version of unix has been increased from 2.2.0.0 to 2.3.0.0.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        The version of Win32 has been increased from 2.1.0.0 to 2.1.1.0.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>

